IVONNE FERNANDEZ

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution Architects professional with graduated degree. Solid knowledge of Cyber security, risk and compliance frameworks, disaster recovery, high availability architectures, hardware, operating systems, networking, and project management.

Some of my roles are: Conduct an architectural system evaluation, analyze technology environment, analyze technical and business requirements, define procedure and process to ensure solution delivery, create a solution prototype, continually researching current and emerging technologies, proposing changes where needed and assessing the business impact that certain technical choices offer.

QUALIFICATIONS and KEY SKILLS

- Highly motivated self-starter with Exceptional analytical, conceptual, and problem-solving abilities
- Adapt to new technologies and learn quick
- Strong organizational and leadership
- Passion for teaching, coaching, and reading
- Fluent in English, Native Spanish.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr Solution Architect

Nov 2013 - Current

Affordabletours.Com, Houston TX

The largest online travel seller of escorted tours, cruises, and river cruises in the USA

- Provided architectural recommendations during the implementation of critical solutions to ensure compliance with policies, standards, and best security practices.
- Worked closely a vendor to migrate Cisco firewall to Palo alto firewall.
- Worked with a network consultant to architect a remote worker platform using Citrix Xen servers,
 Citrix XenDesktop, Citrix NetScaler and Dell Wyse terminals to allow travel consultants to work from
 home. About three years ago, this environment was architected and migrated to Amazon Workspaces
 and Workdocs allowing the company to have a hot site for disaster recovery and business continuity
 purpose.
- Developed the information security program, enterprise-wide security policies, standards, and guidelines to handle sensitive data.
- Designed and Trained new employees in essential cyber security concepts to protect company sensitive data.
- Planned the desktop migration to Microsoft Windows 7 and later to Microsoft Windows 10 for AWS workspaces and on-premises desktops.
- Participated as a leader of the team which planned, designed, and migrated all the platform from windows 2008 to Windows 2012 servers. Also, the network was segmented, DCHP, DNS, Active Directory and Windows deployment services were redesigned.
- Conducted the research and evaluation of multiple cloud PBX products to migrate on premise phone system to a cloud alternative. Later, led the team which planned, designed, and migrated seamless on-premises PBX Avaya to cloud 8x8 for about 120 employees in the call center.

Information System Specialist Conavi , Medellin, Colombia

Jan 1998 – May 2003

Major bank which performed active long term mortgage operations adquired by Bancolombia bank.

- Participated as a member of six-person team who planned, designed, and migrate all the Unix platform to Windows NT servers and Windows 98 computers as a requirement of the year 2000 change for 224 branch offices nationwide.
- Participated as a leader of the team which planned, designed, and migrated all the platform from windows NT 4.0 to Windows 2000 servers, including the email server update to Exchange 2003. It had 226 domain controllers, 160 servers, about 5,000 desktops and 520 ATMs.
- Led, planned, designed, and control implementation of new versions of operating systems (on the windows 2000 and XP Platform), antivirus and Microsoft SMS.
- Designed and wrote the procedure to duplicate the windows XP operating system for all computers and ATMs on 224 bank branches national wide including headquarters.
- Led investigation to find a specified software and hardware to implement an alarm system for the ATMs and bank branches, which must work over a TCP/IP network.
- Performed evaluation and recommendations of tools to be implemented
- Ran performance and capacity on intel server to determine if performance problems exist, and if so, developed the solution.

EDUCATION

- Master of Science in Information System Security, University of Houston, Houston TX, May 15,2015.
- Post Graduate Certificate, Project Management, Pontificia Bolivariana University, Colombia September 4, 2003.
- Bachelor's Degree in Computer Systems Engineering (5 years), San Buenaventura University, Colombia, November 20, 1999.

RELATED COURSES

- 8x8 VCC, VO Admin & Config
- 8x8 VO & VCC Adoption Kit
- Architecting on AWS, Houston
- AWS security Fundamentals,
- Supporting and troubleshooting Windows 10
- Certified Ethical Hacker v10, EC-Council
- Administering Windows Server 2012
- Installing and Configuring Windows Server 2012
- Configuring Advanced Windows Server 2012 Services

PROFESIONAL ASSOCIATIONS

- InfraGard
- Information Systems Security Association (ISSA)